Ahmed Mohamed Reda

Front-End Developer

(+20) 1145809984

□ asayed565565@gmail.com

♥ Giza

in ahmedmohamed165

SUMMARY

Junior front-end with 2 years of experience building websites and web applications using ReactJS and modern JavaScript tools/frameworks. Seeking a challenging and rewarding position as a full stack developer where I can apply my skills in Vue, Node.js, ASP, SQL Server, and Entity Framework to deliver high-quality solutions.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of commerce English section

2016-2020 Cairo University Accounting department GPA: 2.8 (70%)

- Front End Developer (React.js)

October 2023 - February 2024 Route Academy

EXPERIENCE

Merchandise Developer & Help Desk

February 2021 - December 2023

ACTIV ABOU ALAA

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

Merchandise Developer & control

- Review & check the new merchandise and collecting data about it like (supplier description - cost price - quantity) to activate & coding it into the system
- Adjustment prices of the merchandise on the program (discount / sale)
- Main member in stocktaking committee

Help Desk

- Follow-up computers for employees
- Installation and operation of new devices and installation of refrigerators and operating systems
- Ensuring security and efficiency of IT infrastructure
- Install and configure software and hardware
- Set up accounts and workstations

System Administration

February 2018 – June 2020

JEL ACTIV

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Installing and configuring software, hardware and networks
- Monitoring system performance and troubleshooting issues
- Ensuring security and efficiency of IT infrastructure
- Install and configure software and hardware
- Set up accounts and workstations
- Monitor performance and maintain systems according to requirements

TRAINING - COURSES

- Online Courses
 - IT Help desk Web Development (El-Zero) Master Python (El-Zero)
- Python Diploma [Flask-Django Frameworks]

September 2022 – December 2022 IT Sharks

SKILLS

Software Skills:

Languages: Python - HTML – CSS - Java Script - TypeScript

- **Libraries:** React.js – jQuery

- **Frameworks:** Bootstrap

- **Tools:** GitHub - VS Code

Language skills:

- Arabic [Mother tongue] - English [Very Good]

• Personal skills:

Problem solving skills.
 Team player

- Excellent Communication Skills - Research & Analysis

PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENT

Store locator

page for Activ Abou ALAA stores

Portfolio sites

DevFolio (https://ahmedsayedmohamed.github.io/PR3 DevFolio/)
Daniels (https://ahmedsayedmohamed.github.io/PR4 Daniels/)

Random Quotes (https://ahmedsayedmohamed.github.io/PR5 Random-Quotes/)
 Bookmarker (https://ahmedsayedmohamed.github.io/PR6_Bookmarker/)

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

- Date of birth: 16th May 1998 - Military status: Exempted